<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Bytemaster&#39;s Blog</title>
        <description>Join me as I explore free market solutions to secure life, liberty, and property for all.</description>
        <link>/</link>
        <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 18:58:40 +0100</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 18:58:40 +0100</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v2.5.2</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>BitShares as a Bank - The origin of the DAC</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;My father and I were discussing BitShares one evening (fall 2013) and I was trying to describe how BitShares is different from an altcoin.   I used an analogy that described BitShares as a crypto-equity in a decentralized bank and exchange called BitShares.  The shareholders of the bank are those who own bitshares (BTS).   I then went on to explain how this decentralized bank can create dollars just like their centralized counterparts.  I posted a variation of this article on Lets Talk Bitcoin and it launched the concept of a DAC (&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;ecentralized &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;utonomous &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;orporation ).   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then legal worry worts have relabeled the concept of a DAC into DAOs (Organizations)  or simply DAs (Distributed Applications).  I have personal chosen to use many different variations on the DAC acronym to help communicate the many different perspectives that are possible and bring added clarity and precision to the term.   I now use Distributed Automated &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;ompany, &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;ommunity, &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;oop, &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;ountry, or &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;urrency depending on the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview-of-modern-banking&quot;&gt;Overview of Modern Banking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All banks these days operate on what I like to call a &lt;em&gt;fictional&lt;/em&gt; reserve basis.  When you approach the bank for a loan to buy a house, the bank creates new dollars from thin air backed by your collateralized promise to pay back the loan.  In this case, your house is the collateral and the bank may call your loan and foreclose if you stop making the required payments or if the value of the house falls too much.   When you pay off your loan the dollars are destroyed and the bank keeps the interest payments and the lean is removed from your house.   The key thing to remember here is that these dollars are nothing more than an IOU from the bank.   People trust the value of the IOUs because they trust the bank to honor their promise to pay a dollars worth of value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/GoldCoinDollar.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets step back one step further and consider that a dollar use to be defined as  412.5 grains of 99.9% pure silver.   When you received a bank note it was a promise to pay  one dollar worth of gold and the law defined the fixed ratio of gold to silver required to give the bank note a tie to the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see the promise to pay is denominated in dollars which are defined as a weight in silver, and yet what is paid out upon redemption is gold.   This example demonstrates that a dollar is just an arbitrary label assigned to a certain amount of value.  Just like you could have a dollar of silver or a dollar of gold, you could also have a dollar of corn, a dollar of oil, or a dollar of anything including a dollar of bitcoin!   When the United States left the gold standard entirely the dollar began to float against all other goods and services and now has value for its own sake even though it is no longer price-fixed against gold or silver.  The dollar is nothing more than an arbitrary measure of value and is still redeemable for $1 worth of silver at the current market price (not the price fixed 412.5 grains of silver).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitshares-as-a-dac&quot;&gt;BitShares as a DAC&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets go back to the world of decentralized digital companies and consider how a decentralized bank can lend dollars into existence just like their centralized counterparts.   First the bank must identify someone who would like to borrow dollars. The borrower posts the collateral that backs the value of the dollars.    Just like real banks,  BitShares requires collateral for the loan and the only collateral BitShares has the ability to foreclose upon is its own equity, BTS.  It is easier to understand the lending analogy if you consider a home equity loan taken out against a house you already own free and clear.  In normal economic conditions, a Bank will never loan you an amount more than 80% of the value of your house.  If your house is worth $100,000 the most you can borrow in $80,000.   In the case of BitShares if you have $100,000 worth of BTS, the most you can borrow is $33,333.  This is far more conservative than banks, especially considering the collateral (BTS) is far more liquid and fungible than a one-of-a-kind house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BitUSD is the equivalent of the old bank notes that promised to pay $1 worth of value on demand.  In the case of the old bank notes, this value was denominated in gold or silver.  In the case of the BitShares this value is $1 worth of equity, aka BTS.   BitShares can almost always make good on this promise because when someone comes to redeem a note and is unable to sell it on the market directly the value of the BitUSD in terms of BTS will rise until the decentralized bank has the authority to call a loan and use the collateral to repurchase the BitUSD.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people understand why someone would borrow money to buy a house, but why would someone mortgage their BitShares for BitUSD?   The reason someone would borrow BitUSD is so they could sell it and take what is called a short position.  A short position is a speculative bet that BitUSD will go down in value relative to BTS.  If the value does go down then the speculator can repurchase the BitUSD for fewer BTS in the future and then pay off the loan while pocketing a nice profit.  This is how speculators on Wall Street make money when stocks go down: they borrow the stock, sell it for $100, and then repurchase it later for $50 and return the stock while making a $50 profit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dividends--interest-payments&quot;&gt;Dividends &amp;amp; Interest Payments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All banks attempt to operate for a profit and therefore charge interest on loans along with transaction fees and inactivity fees.  The bank profits are the distributed to the shareholders as dividends.  In the case of the BitShares there are also transaction fees, registration fees, margin-call fees, etc. and the profits that result from charging these fees are paid to the shareholders via a stock buyback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone wishes to borrow BitUSD from the bank they do not get to borrow this money interest-free.  Instead they pay interest based upon the market demand for borrowing USD.  The more people that want to borrow BitUSD relative to the people wanting to lend (buy) it the higher the interest rate shorts will pay.  In practice the interest rate on BitUSD will be proportional to the short term growth expectations of BTS and the relative demand for leverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is through this explanation of BitShares that the concept of a Decentralized Autonomous Company was born and a new take on the nature of Bitcoin as a decentralized autonomous company rather than just a crypto-currency came to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;recent-developments&quot;&gt;Recent Developments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When this article was originally written (Fall 2013) the concept of a DAC was very young.  Since that time the analogy has been expanded upon and the metaphor has lead to major advancements in the crypto currency space including: Delegated Proof of Stake which eliminated mining and enabled dilution as a means to permanently fund the growth and development of decentralized businesses.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Max Wright in is book &lt;a href=&quot;/article/2014/12/20/BitShares-101.html&quot;&gt;BitShares 101&lt;/a&gt; goes into much greater detail in describing DACs as it relates to what BitShares is today. In his book he describes how Bitcoin is a DAC and provides great detail about the power of Delegated Proof of Stake (DPOS).  I highly recommend you check it out.   &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>/article/2014/12/20/BitShares-as-a-Bank/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/article/2014/12/20/BitShares-as-a-Bank/</guid>
                
                
                    <category>article</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Introducing BitShares.TV</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bitshares.tv&quot;&gt;BitShares.TV&lt;/a&gt; hosted by Max Wright, is a weekly internet show dedicated to keeping you up-to-date with the world of BitShares. The first 3 episodes are online and ready for you to watch right now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each episode is designed to give insight to a particular aspect of the BitShares eco system. How BitShares can improve the world we contract, interact, and do business with.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BitShares.TV gives you the inside scoop on the latest developments and allows you to meet the people behind BitShares, from core developers to marketing professionals. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because different aspects of Bitshares appeal to different folks, Bitshares.TV is a great tool to share with your friends to help them get as excited about BitShares as we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And once a BitShares.TV episode sparks a light bulb in someones mind, they are more likely to share it, and get involved… and that is exactly what we want.  I hope the TV show will spark enough interest that they understand and get involved in BitShares.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>/article/2014/12/20/BitShares-TV/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/article/2014/12/20/BitShares-TV/</guid>
                
                
                    <category>article</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>&#39;BitShares 101&#39; Book Released</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Max Wright has just published the first e-book about BitShares: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/BitShares-101-Generation-Currencies-Decentralized-ebook/dp/B00QUIWHR0/&quot;&gt;“BitShares 101”&lt;/a&gt;.  For a long time 
the BitShares community has needed a introductory guide for the average man. Max
has done an amazing job taking a complex subject and condensing it down into 
something easily understood.  His writing style is very conversational and easy
to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this ~59 page book you will find clear explanations of things such as
Decentralized Autonomous Companies (DACs).  An overview of &lt;a href=&quot;/update/2014/12/18/What-is-BitShares.html&quot;&gt;BitShares&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;/article/2014/12/18/What-are-BitShares-Market-Pegged-Assets.html&quot;&gt;BitAssets&lt;/a&gt; is provided
that takes a slightly different approach at describing BitShares than I did in
my post on &lt;a href=&quot;/update/2014/12/18/What-is-BitShares.html&quot;&gt;“What is BitShares?”&lt;/a&gt;.  In his
approach he describes BitShares using the company metaphor.  This is perhaps
the most useful approach to understanding BitShares from the perspective of an
investor. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to understand the value proposition of BitShares this is the book for you. If
want to understand the philosophy of BitShares then my blog is the place for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is currently available for $0.99 on Amazon Kindle.  Max is selling the book for
the sole purpose of getting free advertising on the Amazon best sellers list for 
various categories.   Even if you already know everything there is to know about
BitShares I highly recommend you buy the book as a way of supporting our community and
providing Max with a tip for the excellent work has produced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitsharestv&quot;&gt;BitShares.TV&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you who don’t know, Max has also launched a video at &lt;a href=&quot;http://bitshares.tv&quot;&gt;BitShares.TV&lt;/a&gt; covering 
BitShares related topics.  His video blog is the analog of my written blog. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;620&quot; height=&quot;349&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/XxTtW44R_bQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>/article/2014/12/20/BitShares-101/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/article/2014/12/20/BitShares-101/</guid>
                
                
                    <category>article</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Aggregate Public Opinion Matters</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Whether we like it or not the mob ultimately runs society.  Individual property rights mean nothing in a riot.   If public opinion turns against something nothing can resist it for long, not even the most oppressive governments.  A libertarian utopia is the result of changing public opinion and maintaining public support for universal application of the &lt;a href=&quot;/article/2014/12/16/Golden-Principle.html&quot;&gt;Golden Principle&lt;/a&gt; without exception. If you haven’t read my post on the Golden Principle I recommend you check it out.     &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately most people do not form their opinion based upon facts and reason, but instead defer to the opinions of others.  Each and every day people make decisions based upon what they think other people think.   Style, language, morals, religion, politics, and just about everything are heavily influenced by other peoples opinions.   When in doubt most people defer to public opinion over their own opinion and this is the heart of democracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Billions of dollars are spent every single year in an effort to shape and then measure the aggregate opinion of the entire population on politics alone.   There is an entire field of study dedicated to the manipulation of pubic opinion for profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the more sophisticated techniques of manipulating opinion is by corrupting the measuring and reporting process.   If you can control the major media outlets and continuously show support of a minority opinion over a majority opinion then people will come to believe that the minority opinion is the majority opinion.   This can either be subtle or overt.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps one of the most overt attempts to manipulate public opinion is the corruption of “scientific polling” prior to elections or the elections themselves.   As a result of publishing these scientific polls people conclude that some candidates are unelectable while others are extremely popular even if they are not.  If you can manipulate an election then you can change the very constitution of a society while facing limited opposition. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one likes to be a minority that stands out against the majority.  They will often publicly support the majority opinion even if they privately object.  This creates a self reinforcing cycle that results in the quiet suffering and repression of the majority. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we are to achieve a libertarian utopia it becomes critical that the market produce an actuate and fully trustworthy measurement of the aggregate opinion.   A private, incorruptible, continuous polling of the population would provide a means for people to feel safe communicating their desire to change the way society operates.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately with the combination of the internet and modern cryptography we now have the tools necessary to produce a nearly incorruptible anonymous polling solution.   &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>/article/2014/12/20/Aggregate-Public-Opinion-Matters/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/article/2014/12/20/Aggregate-Public-Opinion-Matters/</guid>
                
                
                    <category>article</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Value of DevShares</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Block chain technology is constantly evolving and while Bitcoin appears content to stand still, we feel BitShares needs to be more dynamic so it can evolve with the market.   Stability and predictability are core features of any block chain and any interruption in service can have a dramatic effect on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: right&quot; src=&quot;/media/upgrade_comic.png&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a saying that no upgrade goes unpunished.  And despite the best efforts of large companies such as Apple, they still have the occasional bug introduced by an upgrade.  All of the testing in the world is unable to find every bug or test every environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My fellow developers and I face a similar challenge with BitShares.   We have test cases, unit tests, regression tests, test networks, and peer reviews, but they are unable to fully cover all potential bugs.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps one of the most difficult bugs to track down are bugs in the upgrade process itself.  When we migrate from one version of BitShares to another there is often some small amount of glue code that manages the transition from one set of block chain rules to another.   The only place this glue code can be tested is on the real network.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some bugs only show up on user machines, on some operating systems, or worst of all only when the right combination of machines each running slightly different versions of our software.  The odds are against our developers being able to find everything, yet the cost of bugs is higher than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introducing-devshares&quot;&gt;Introducing DevShares&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DevShares is our effort at simulating the conditions of the real BitShares network as closely as possible so that we can test every upgrade throughly prior to upgrading BitShares.  To do this we need a live network, with delegates around the world upon which BitAssets are trading.  We need a network that has real value and real users who are experimenting with every proposed update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In may ways BitShares has been operating as a live development network over the course of the past five months.  We have been upgrading it every couple of weeks and from time to time one of our upgrades goes wrong and we have to follow it with a rapid patch.  This process has been frustrating for users and our business partners who have a difficult time keeping up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DevShares is designed to off load a lot of the upgrade uncertainty from the BitShares network; therefore, DevShares will be identical to BitShares in almost every respect except for the block numbers that upgrades occur at.    Once DevShares reaches a stable and tested version, we will migrate the code to BitShares and keep the changes to a single number in a single file: the block number at which the upgrade should happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-devshares-have-value&quot;&gt;Why DevShares Have Value&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering the risks of an upgrade going poorly and the potential for a rapid update cycle, why would anyone value DevShares?   It boils down to one simple reason, we are not the only ones who need a test network.  Our exchange partners, merchants, plugins, block explorers, etc. all need a solid testing network.   If you are going to test then you will need to pay some transaction fees on the DevShares network.    If you want to beta test your product on a live network with real users prior to the feature being adopted by BitShares proper, then you will want DevShares.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is no different than early Bitcoin test networks that started to gain value as an alt-coin.  The Bitcoin developers had to modify the block chain in such a way as to prevent it from being imbued with value by the market.     &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the Bitcoin test network, we really do need and want DevShares to have some real value because only through having real value will a distributed user base actively test it; especially the market features.   You cannot test BitAssets throughly unless the collateral has value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;delegate-training-ground&quot;&gt;Delegate Training Ground&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DevShares provides a training ground for new delegates who may one day hope to get elected on the BitShares network.   Most delegates on the BitShares network should be expected to also host at least one node on the test network.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All delegates can then test and debug their upgrade process on the DevShares network and help find and report issues.   If delegates are experimenting with automated fail overs or other infrastructure they will want to make sure it doesn’t inadvertently harm the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DevShares network will have lower value and thus will pay delegates 500 DVS (vs 50 BTS) per block which will result in a much higher initial dilution (up to 60% per year).  This pay will help compensate delegates that participate in testing and generate some spare DVS that they can distribute to those who need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;community-driven&quot;&gt;Community Driven&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like the DevShares network to be a place for the community to drive adoption and marketing.   Give away threads, free samples, etc. open the door for our community to try out new systems without risking the BitShares network directly.    The core developers will be looking to the community to help test every version, to practice their trading skills, and otherwise use the network.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will probably offer bounties for bugs found on the DevShares network and this will help everyone.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitshares-grows-up&quot;&gt;BitShares grows Up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DevShares is the first step toward BitShares growing up to act like a mature production ready environment that people can trust.   The very existence of DevShares and the public testing that it represents will help the market gain confidence in upgrading the BitShares network.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;initial-allocation&quot;&gt;Initial Allocation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The network will be initially allocated as 2 billion shares divided equally among AGS, PTS, and BTS holders as of the December 14th snapshot date.   An additional 50 million vesting shares will be allocated the same was as the 500 million vesting shares in BTS.   These vesting shares are there so that we can throughly test all operations that deal with vesting balances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;expectations&quot;&gt;Expectations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DevShares will undoubtedly be listed on exchanges and many gateways will probably pop up to support the network.  It is important that everyone who is participating in the DevShares network understands that all user issued assets on the DevShares network should be “contract free” and if a bug happens to result in a massive loss to the issuer, the issuer is free to take what ever action they deem appropriate to make people whole (or not).   Any gains or losses as a result of a bug on the DevShares network are part of the system and no one shall be held responsible for any losses.  No one can execute a scam on the DevShares network because all such scams are deemed to be legitimate voluntary choices in a contract free world.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important that you have your expectations set right here.  Exchanges may freely walk away with your DevShares deposits without any moral issues.  When you transfer your funds to the exchange they become the exchanges and are not an IOU.   If an exchange loses your transaction or suffers a loss due to a bug or double spend then that is just your luck.  It is a development network and all operations and transactions are inherently a gamble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel this kind of disclaimer is necessary to encourage exchanges to participate in our development network without fear of any liability.   Some people will have a hard time managing their expectations, but it will be up to the community to remind them of the social consensus on the DevShares chain that there are no scams, “theft” is legitimate, and trust is a gamble.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DevShares network will launch this week and we will start using it for all proposed upgrades to the BitShares network.   If you would like to experiment with our latest beta features then DevShares is the place to be. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>/update/2014/12/19/The-Value-of-DevShares/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/update/2014/12/19/The-Value-of-DevShares/</guid>
                
                
                    <category>update</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>How to Create a Free Society</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating a free society is the combined result of individuals giving each other freedom.  You have heard it said, “give, and ye shall receive”, this is the foundation of a free society.   You have to give others freedom so that they can give you freedom.   Our freedom or lack thereof is the result of millions of actions (or inactions) of millions of people.   Why should we place the blame on government, when government exists only because of the passive consent of the masses?    The government is only an idea, an illusion, and it acts solely through individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float: right&quot; src=&quot;/media/bethechange.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you realize it or not we all contribute to the enslavement of our fellow man in very subtle ways every single day.  The world banking systems are designed from the ground up to provide almost unlimited funding for war and bureaucratic tyranny.   The fiat money created by the world banking systems only has value because we, as individuals, choose to hold and value it.  In other words, by holding and saving fiat money we are actively working against our own goals of creating a free society.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately we all know how hard it is to live without fiat money.   For decades liberty activists have been promoting gold and silver but it was never able to gain traction.  We live in a digital world with great wealth which makes the relative value of an oz of gold or silver too large for many purchases.  Imagine having to round every purchase to 1/10th an oz of silver ($1.28 or more).  Imagine having to purchase everything with physical silver?   It just doesn’t work in the Internet age without trusting a third party bank.  Unfortunately the market has discovered that gold and silver banks may start out as 100% reserve, but reserves gradually fall as governments permit fractional reserve banking.   Today efforts to reset the system such as e-gold and now &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitreserve.org/&quot;&gt;BitReserve&lt;/a&gt; find their 100% reserves are subject to confiscation.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life has taught me that you cannot simply get rid of something in your life, you need to replace it with something else.  Fortunately since the invention of &lt;a href=&quot;http://bitcoin.org&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; and now &lt;a href=&quot;http://bitshares.org&quot;&gt;BitShares&lt;/a&gt; and its &lt;a href=&quot;/article/2014/12/18/What-are-BitShares-Market-Pegged-Assets.html&quot;&gt;BitAssets&lt;/a&gt; we have an alternative.  Now all we need is for people to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;give-people-the-option-to-be-free&quot;&gt;Give people the Option to be Free&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you enter the market as a business man or customer you have a choice on whether or not you will support the freedom of those you interact with.   If you are selling goods or services but require payment through VISA or MasterCard then you are contributing to the overall invisible fence that is keeping people enslaved to the fiat money masters.    You are denying your services to the free economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a customer and are only willing to pay with VISA or MasterCard then you are contributing to the market pressure that forces businesses into the hands of the banking system.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only way for a society to free itself from the grip of the banking system is if we can create a self sustaining, closed loop, economy without them.   Early on this process depends upon freedom lovers everywhere giving people the option to be free by accepting both fiat and BitShares.   Over time freedom lovers will be able to shun the corrupt banking system entirely without significantly impacting their lifestyle.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being an early adopter isn’t easy.  Accepting BitUSD will probably add some costs and uncertainty to your business at first.   You may even lose money on spreads and overhead for a long time.    Few investments produce returns immediately so why should investing your time and energy into learning how to use BItShares be any different?   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately your investment in becoming a BitShares early adopter will yield fantastic returns for your own individual freedom.  You will reap far more than you sow.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt; “Remember this: Whoever sows sparingly will also reap sparingly, and whoever sows generously will also reap generously. Each of you should give what you have decided in your heart to give, not reluctantly or under compulsion”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Give, and it will be given to you. A good measure, pressed down, shaken together and running over, will be poured into your lap. For with the measure you use, it will be measured to you”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When ever you grant others freedom to opt out of the system, you make it easier for others to opt into the BitShares alternative.  The more people that join the BitShares ecosystem the easier it will be for you to opt out the corrupt banker system.   This process has been well studied and is known as &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metcalfe%27s_law&quot;&gt;Metcalfe’s Law&lt;/a&gt;.  The value of a network (community) grows with order N^2 the number of people that are part of it.  When you join the community you add 1 to N and thus produce value far in excess of your individual contribution.  Rarely is it so easy to see in mathematical terms how directly you can reap more than you sow.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;going-beyond-money&quot;&gt;Going Beyond Money&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money is not the only way in which the world systems are conspiring against us to deny us the fruits of our labor and thus our freedom.    Every time you do business on the basis of contracts subject to enforcement by government courts you are forcing people into the corrupt, expensive, and arbitrary legal system.   Do you give your customers the option of arbitration?  Do you advertise your desire to use alternative dispute resolution?   Do you rely on governments to enforce the arbitration outcome or do you participate in free market, non-violent, alternatives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you hire someone or screen a potential tenant or landlord do you use the government background checks?  What about free market background checks on reputation?  Do you participate in the shunning of individuals who have been found guilty in arbitration but failed to voluntarily comply?  Are you bonded to show your commitment to an alternative justice system?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With BitShares we are starting something much bigger than providing a new money alternative, but its success depends upon individuals deciding to opt in, one at a time.  It depends upon each individual choosing to contribute to the freedom of others first so that in time they can achieve their own freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-easy-way&quot;&gt;The “Easy” Way&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could always wait for others to move first.  Wait to be given your freedom by others before you consider returning the favor.  The trouble with this path is that from a &lt;a href=&quot;/article/2007/09/22/Subjective-Reality-Simplified.html&quot;&gt;subjective view of reality&lt;/a&gt;, the outside world is merely a reflection of your inner self.   If you would like to see a change in the outside world then you have to start acting in ways that support your desire or it may never happen.   It is a catch-22. If you attempt to wait for others to move first, then chances are it will never happen.  So if you want freedom you must take action to give others freedom today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;buying-bitshares-bts-supports-freedom&quot;&gt;Buying BitShares (BTS) supports Freedom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you buy BitShares you are providing financial support to 101 elected delegates which are actively working to produce the tools that will secure your freedom.  Without the continued support of people willing to buy and hold BitShares delegates would be unable to work full time and the rate at which the tools of freedom can be built will be dramatically slowed.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately buying BitShares is not self sacrificing, but should yield tremendous returns as our community grows and more people decide to join our cause.   It is one thing to donate to LewRockwell.com, mises.org, or any other charity hoping to feed the poor. It is something else entirely to fund solutions that can magnify the impact of your contribution.   In those cases you get nothing but a warm fuzzy in return.  It can be hard to give a lot.  We all know that profit is critical to growth so buying BitShares provides a direct profit to our early supporters for helping bootstrap a free society.   So when you buy BTS you get a warm fuzzy and an investment opportunity.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you give $5 to a poor man you may feed him for a day, but if you spend $5 buying BitShares you are investing in the tools that can facilitate the economic growth necessary to bring millions out of poverty.   If we are successful then you will be able to feed 1000 poor men for a day in a few years.    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;buying-bitusd-supports-freedom&quot;&gt;Buying BitUSD supports Freedom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you are not one willing to take a huge risk on our movement, but you really want to help support the cause.  Buying BitUSD will allow you to earn a steady return on your $5 without taking much risk at all.  In this case you are voting with your economic power to support our cause.  You can &lt;a href=&quot;/article/2014/12/18/What-are-BitShares-Market-Pegged-Assets.html&quot;&gt;read more about how BitUSD (or BitGold) is a relatively low risk&lt;/a&gt; way to support our community and help secure your own freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no short cuts in life.  It is up to each one of us to stop blaming others for our lack of freedom and start taking personal responsibility for the tyranny we see in the world.  For my part I hope the use this blog to show the way with real, practical, and profitable alternatives that can be implemented today.  Will you join us?  What have you got to lose?  &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>/article/2014/12/19/How-to-Create-a-Free-Society/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/article/2014/12/19/How-to-Create-a-Free-Society/</guid>
                
                
                    <category>article</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>What Is Bitshares</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Answering the question “What is BitShares?” has been one of the most difficult challenges I have faced.  BitShares is so many things to different people and there are a thousand different ways of understanding what BitShares is.  This post will tell you what BitShares is to me, its founder.  Before getting into the long-answer to this question, let me give you the executive summary.   BitShares is one of the most important tools that any community can use to secure their freedom; an idea whose time has come. After reading this post I bet you will agree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All the forces in the world are not so powerful as an idea whose time has come.  - Victor Hugo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many different layers at which we can understand BitShares.  Each layer has its own benefit and usefulness. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/BitSharesIsLikeAnOnion.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BitShares is like an Onion&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitshares-is-software&quot;&gt;BitShares is software&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its most inner layer, &lt;strong&gt;BitShares is software&lt;/strong&gt;.  To be more specific, BitShares is a distributed multi-user database with update permissions managed by a defined set of rules and public key cryptography.   At this level it isn’t very interesting to most people, but is still very important.  Software is open source, easily copied and modified, and most importantly protected by free speech.  This means that almost nothing can stop BitShares at this layer short of a global event that destroys almost all digital data.  Governments once attempted to regulate cryptographic software as a weapon and impose export controls.  Governments lost that battle long ago and no longer attempt to regulate or control the spread of free software.  In the case of BitShares the software is in the &lt;a href=&quot;/update/2014/12/17/Why-Public-Domain.html&quot;&gt;Public Domain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitshares-is-a-network&quot;&gt;BitShares is a network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving up a layer, &lt;strong&gt;BitShares is a network&lt;/strong&gt;.  A network of computers owned by individuals all over the world run the BitShares software and keep their databases synchronized according to the rules defined by the software.  The BitShares network can survive as long as there are at least two computers that can communicate with each other over the internet.  This network of distributed computers ensures that the database is robust against failure.  Every single computer on the network maintains a full copy of the database which means no one can change the public record.  This immutable public record becomes the foundation of higher layers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitshares-is-a-ledger&quot;&gt;BitShares is a Ledger&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A ledger is a database containing account balances and transfers among them.  Every bank, company, and organization that deals in financial matters has a ledger that tracks who owns what.   The BitShares ledger is very robust because it is built on the prior two layers: highly distributed network, that is fully transparent, and secured by the latest cryptography.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compare this to ledgers in use all around the world today.  Ledgers based upon paper can be lost, stolen, modified, burned, or miscalculated.  Digital ledgers managed by software such as Quick Books or Quicken are centrally managed, can be updated, changed, back dated, corrupted or otherwise misused.  Advanced ledgers such as is in use by our banking system are still subject to human error, lack transparency, are only backed up a hand full of places and often times are internally inconsistent.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just ask the owners of MF Global where the depositors’ funds went?  Ask any of the big banks who really owns the gold and how many times the same ounce of gold has been used as collateral; they cannot tell you with any degree of certainty.  The ledgers in use today around the world are fundamentally broken when it comes to reliably tracking property rights.  How do we know they are broken? Have you ever heard of cooking the books?  Today’s ledgers have insufficient technological barriers against fraudulent edits; the ultimate protection is a manual audit, but audits are time-consuming, expensive, non-public and only as trustworthy as the auditor (think about Enron).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BitShares ledger changes the game by providing a badly needed advancement in accountability. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitshares-is-a-company&quot;&gt;BitShares is a Company&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies are merely a ledger tracking joint ownership in a common venture.  Companies issue stock which is nothing more than a ledger entry tracking what percent of the company each individual owns.  Companies are managed by a board of directors which is elected by the shareholders, the votes of which are logged in the companies ledger. Companies have a business model that hopes to earn profit for the shareholders and they maintain detailed records of all business transactions which, in theory, can be audited by the shareholders to ensure management isn’t embezzling money. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of BitShares, the database tracks ownership of shares known as BTS.  Each share can vote for 110 delegates, the top 101 delegates by vote become responsible for running the software and maintaining the network as well as performing other tasks for which they are paid by the shareholders.  BitShares is a company in the business of processing transactions for a fee and the profits from this business are shared with the shareholders via stock buybacks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitshares-is-an-exchange&quot;&gt;BitShares is an Exchange&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The New York Stock exchange is a company that maintains a ledger to track ownership of stock and debt issued by other companies. It earns money from transaction fees and has its own stock as well.   Like the New York Stock exchange, BitShares allows people to issue their stock or debt to be tracked and traded on its distributed ledger.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitshares-is-a-bank&quot;&gt;BitShares is a Bank&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks are companies that maintain a ledger to track debt collateralized by other assets such as housing.  This debt is the money used around the world, denominated in dollars, euros, yuan, etc.  Banks earn income by charging interest to the borrowers and attract capital by paying interest to depositors.  BitShares creates dollar denominated debt collateralized by BTS.  This dollar denominated debt is a &lt;a href=&quot;/article/2014/12/18/What-are-BitShares-Market-Pegged-Assets.html&quot;&gt;BitAsset&lt;/a&gt; known as BitUSD.  BitShares supports any number of BitAssets including BitGold, BitSilver, BitOil, etc.  Whereas normal banks practice the unsustainable business of fractional reserve banking, BitShares uses at least 200% reserve and is often over 300% reserve.  Whereas normal banks use illiquid assets to back (collateralize) debt payable on demand, BitShares uses highly liquid BTS as collateral.   Whereas normal banks are bailed out by tax payers, BitShares depositors have direct claim on the collateral.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall BitShares is better banking. Lance Kasper wrote a detailed article explaining how &lt;a href=&quot;/article/2014/12/18/What-are-BitShares-Market-Pegged-Assets.html&quot;&gt;BitShares Market Pegged Assets&lt;/a&gt; operate.  I highly recommend the article to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitshares-is-a-currency&quot;&gt;BitShares is a Currency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything can be used as money in the right circumstances.  Gold, silver, giant stones, paper, debt, and cigarettes have all been used as money.  The rich and powerful have often used &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.investopedia.com/terms/b/bearer_share.asp&quot;&gt;bearer shares&lt;/a&gt; (paper stock certificates) as a form of money.  In the case of BitShares there are many different assets that can be used as money including BTS, BitUSD, BitGold, and BitSilver.   All of these assets have the property of being fungible, divisible, transportable, and impossible to counterfeit.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have previously said that the best money is like a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Back-Future-Capacitor-Replica-Unlimited/dp/B001M5PTQM&quot;&gt;Flux Capacitor&lt;/a&gt;.  It can move value though time and space as quickly as possible with minimal loss.  Gold is great at moving value though time, as demonstrated by the fact that gold mined 1000 years ago is still worth something today.  Fiat currencies produced by governments have a shelf life of less than 100 years, during which they slowly lose all of their value.  Unfortunately, gold and paper money are not very efficient at moving value through space.  Physically moving boxes of gold or hundred dollar bills long distances or across borders is very time consuming and expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bank deposits are very efficient at moving value through space via wire transfers, but they are still expensive and relatively slow (days). Bank deposits can also lose all of their value far more often than paper dollars because banks regularly go bankrupt. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With BitShares and BitGold, you get many properties of gold (such as price stability and freedom from counter-party risk), as well as the benefits of bank deposits (you can transfer millions of dollars worth of BitGold to the other side of the world in seconds).   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you use BitShares (BTS) as virtual bearer shares, BitGold as a 300% collateralized virtual gold deposit, or BitUSD as an alternative to fractional reserve bank deposits, BitShares provides the best money/currency in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitshares-is-a-community&quot;&gt;BitShares is a Community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A piece of software powering a distributed network is worthless without people coming together to give value to the BTS on the ledger entries.  Each and every person that joins the BitShares community adds value to the ledger and gains value from the fellow community members.   All things start small with just a few people.  Over the past year and a half, BitShares has grown from an idea to a global community with thousands of people.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communities are brought together around common values and principles.  They support each other through thick and thin.  As the founder of BitShares, this community is largely brought together by the principles I espouse on this blog:  Creating decentralized, market-based solutions to secure life, liberty, and property for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitshares-is-a-country&quot;&gt;BitShares is a Country&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Countries are what communities become when they become large enough and powerful enough.  Countries are sovereign and issue their own currency.  Countries are run by elected governments, usually with some kind of senate or parliament like BitShares’ delegates.  While we have a long way to go, it is my vision to grow BitShares to the point where the ecosystem is able to make governments irrelevant to our daily lives.  This means all dispute resolution and law enforcement will be managed by the BitShares community in an entirely non-violent manner by leveraging smart contracts, bonds, insurance, and other systems on the BitShares ledger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitshares-is-an-idea&quot;&gt;BitShares is an Idea…&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…whose time has come.  The specific software, network, and ledger that BitShares is today has very real limitations.  But the &lt;em&gt;idea&lt;/em&gt; behind BitShares, BitAssets, and non-violent self governance is so powerful that all the forces in the world cannot stop it.  The &lt;em&gt;idea&lt;/em&gt; will live on in one form or another.  The entire concept of numbers on a ledger having value exists entirely in the collective mind of the BitShares community.  It doesn’t matter what form that ledger takes, what matters is that we all share a common idea regarding who owns what.  We no longer rely on governments to be the arbiter of property rights.  BitShares, the software, is just a tool that enables our community to reach unambiguous consensus on property rights.  In many ways, it is no different than &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rai_stones&quot;&gt;Rai stones&lt;/a&gt; which are large immovable stones used as money which were valued because of community consensus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BitShares is a small town on global scale.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our community is open to all who wish to create a free society where our children can be secure in life, liberty, and property.  Join us and be a part of the solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>/update/2014/12/18/What-is-BitShares/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/update/2014/12/18/What-is-BitShares/</guid>
                
                
                    <category>update</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>What are BitShares Market Pegged Assets?</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;BitShares market pegged assets are a new type of freely traded digital asset whose value is meant to track the value of a conventional asset such as the U.S. dollar or gold.  What makes market pegged assets unique is that they are free from counter party risk.  BitShares uses an advanced decentralized consensus ledger that takes some cues from Bitcoin.  While Bitcoin has demonstrated many useful properties as a currency, its price volatility makes it risky to hold and difficult to use for everyday pricing and payments.  A currency with the properties and advantages of Bitcoin that maintains price parity with a globally adopted currency such as the US dollar has high utility for convenient and censorship resistant commerce.  This paper will explain how market pegged assets including “BitUSD” (intended to track the value of the US dollar) achieve price parity while minimizing risk to holders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;price-stability&quot;&gt;Price Stability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin and similar crypto-currencies track transferrable digital tokens secured by private cryptographic keys over a decentralized computer network.  A consensus mechanism ensures tokens are not duplicated and all participants agree on the state of the system without need for a central validating authority.  This consensus is recorded on a decentralized shared ledger called a “block chain”.  These systems have been found to enable value storage and exchange over the internet beyond the control or censorship of a centralized party.  Demand for this utility has driven up the price of crypto-currencies.  BitShares uses an analogous core token simply called BitShares that is traded with the abbreviation “BTS” on well-known crypto-currency exchanges.  Like Bitcoin, the exchange rate between BTS and major currencies remains volatile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A BitShares market pegged asset can be viewed as a contract between an asset buyer seeking price stability and a “short seller” seeking greater exposure to BTS price movement.  The open source BitShares software program implements a decentralized marketplace for market pegged assets where all transactions are recorded on the shared block chain ledger and the software enforces the market rules.  This block chain based marketplace is referred to as the “internal market” to distinguish from “external markets” such as websites that facilitate the exchange of government issued currencies with crypto-currency.  A BTS holder may use her BTS to place a buy order on this internal market for her asset of choice.  Market pegged assets are created on the BitShares block chain when a buyer and short seller of an asset are matched at an agreed price.  In exchange for the BTS received from the asset buyer the short seller takes on the obligation of buying back the same quantity of assets in the future from the market.  BTS paid by the asset buyer and additional BTS contributed by the short seller are sequestered as “collateral”.   This collateral is only returned to the short seller when assets are purchased back from the market and effectively destroyed to fulfill the contract.  This is referred to as “covering a short.”  If the value of the collateral relative to the current price of the market pegged asset falls below a certain margin of safety the assets can be automatically repurchased from the market before collateral becomes insufficient.  These rules create systemic demand for market pegged assets while allowing them to remain fungible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rules considered thus far do not specifically restrict the internal exchange rate between BitUSD and BTS in a way that ensures it will track the external exchange rate between USD and BTS.  A first step toward this goal is to get reliable information about the external exchange rate into the internal market algorithm.  It is not immediately obvious how this is accomplished in a way that is resistant to control and manipulation by a central party.  Thankfully, the consensus mechanism used for BitShares utilizes a carefully considered real-time stake-weighted approval voting system to elect “delegates” who are motivated to act in the best interest of the system and its stakeholders.  These delegates run computers on the BitShares network that check and commit broadcasted transactions to the block chain ledger.  The trusted delegates can also be used to input external exchange rates into the block chain so that the software algorithm can incorporate this information into the market rules.  This external exchange rate information is called a “price feed.”  Delegates typically combine price information from multiple sources, such as external exchanges, to generate a price feed and update it regularly.  The system takes a median of all price feeds so that manipulation of the price information would be very difficult by any single delegate or party without considerable collusion.  The price feed and other delegate behavior is publically auditable and delegates may be voted out by BTS holders at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to consider how the price feed can be used to regulate the internal market.  Both BTS and market pegged assets are freely transferrable tokens.  If the internal market restricted trading to occur only at the specific exchange rate determined by the median price feed, it would simply encourage anyone willing to trade at a different price to do so outside the system, such as on an external exchange.  However, if we consider that short selling is the mechanism by which new market pegged assets are created, then selectively restricting short selling controls the conditions under which supply is created.  Rather than allow short sellers to sell at any price, short sellers will only execute at a price above the median price feed.  This prevents short sellers from devaluing market pegged assets as new assets are only created when the market demand pushes the price equal to or above parity.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The price feed functions to regulate creation and destruction of market pegged assets in a way that pushes the market price toward parity.  When a short seller buys back BitUSD and covers their position they are taking BitUSD out of circulation and reducing the total supply.  In fact, the current BitShares market rules force short sellers to cover their position within 30 days of opening the position.  This means that the full amount of outstanding BitUSD must be purchased off the market every 30 days.  Market pegged asset holders have no requirement to sell and therefore short sellers covering their positions are eventually forced to purchase from newly opened short positions at or above the exchange rate.   This is effectively a guarantee to any BitUSD holder that they can sell BitUSD for the dollar equivalent of BTS (determined by price feed) within any 30 day period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The motivation to participate in the system is different for short sellers and market pegged asset buyers.  Market pegged asset holders are typically looking for predictable value coupled with the properties of a crypto-currency.  Short sellers are typically bullish on the price of BTS and wish to capitalize on increased exposure to market movement relative to the market pegged asset.  If the market value of BTS rises with respect to the asset, the short seller can buy back the asset for significantly less BTS and profit accordingly.  If BTS value falls in relation to the market pegged asset, the short seller faces a greater loss than if they were to have simply held BTS.  Ultimately a short seller may face a “margin call” where his collateral is automatically used repay the obligation.  A margin call is triggered in the current BitShares system whenever collateral contains less than 1.5 times the amount of BTS required to cover the obligation.  The system also charges an additional 5% fee to any short seller subject to a margin call and this fee is intended to motivate short sellers to maintain sufficient collateral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;order-matching&quot;&gt;Order Matching&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Market orders and other signed transactions on the BitShares block chain are grouped into 10 second blocks by delegates.  When buy and sell orders on the internal BitShares’ market are matched, the highest buy orders are matched with the lowest sell orders and any BTS contained in the overlap are destroyed so that each party gets exactly what they paid for.  The reason for this is twofold.  Firstly, it prevents high frequency trading that attempts to insert an order between two placed orders to profit from the overlap, this is sometimes called “front running”.  It also makes it very costly for a large buyer or seller to quickly move the market by placing a large order far from the current market rate.  Doing so would require the buyer or seller to pay the more expensive rate and lose any overlap with all orders their order is matched with.  The destruction of BTS from the overlap of orders creates value for BTS holders as a whole by making the token more scarce.  When there is significant demand to short sell assets at the price feed rate, the current BitShares system allows short sellers to offer interest to asset holders in exchange for priority in order matching.  In this way, holders of market pegged assets can also collect an additional yield on their savings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;risk&quot;&gt;Risk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current implementation of market pegged assets in the BitShares system is designed to minimize risk of loss to market pegged asset holders.  Short positions are opened with collateral worth three times the market value of the asset.  The initial collateral is comprised of the BTS paid by the buyer for the asset and twice this amount of BTS contributed by the short seller.   The collateral requirements and margin triggers were chosen conservatively to protect the holders of market pegged assets from volatility of the underlying collateral.   Forcing short positions to cover every 30 days provides additional assurance of short term liquidity.  Control over the price feed is distributed among over 50 separately elected delegates who compile information from multiple exchange sources.  Despite such precautions, it is important to carefully explore risks of using the system.  Risks can be broadly categorized as value risk, counterparty risk, or systemic risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;collateral-risk&quot;&gt;Collateral Risk:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Market pegged assets maintain their price parity due to being backed by collateral that has an established real world value.  When the value of the collateral falls, the system is designed to react by driving the internal asset exchange to match the new real world exchange rate and trigger margin calls as necessary.  However, there exists a possibility that the underlying collateral (BTS) drops in value so quickly the market pegged assets become under-collateralized.  Often termed a “black swan event,” a sudden crash of BTS value could prevent the system from adjusting in time.  In this event, the full amount of collateral is no longer sufficient to purchase the market pegged asset back at the new real exchange rate.  In such an event, assets may trade below their face value.  It is possible the market could recover if BTS regained value.  It is also possible the market would need to be “reset” and asset holders forced to settle for BTS collateral worth less than the intended face value of their assets.  Under normal conditions, short term market movements, spreads, and fees charged by exchanges may also affect the potential cost of conversion into and out of market pegged assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;counterparty-risk&quot;&gt;Counterparty risk:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike many attempts to create a digital asset that tracks the dollar, market pegged asset are not an “I owe you” issued by any entity.  For this reason, it does not rely on a specific counterparty to honor its value.  Although manipulation risk occurs in any market, it is minimized by the open source and auditable nature of the BitShares system and carefully considered market rules.  BitAssets stored on an exchange become IOUs and are subject to counter party risk just like storing bitcoin or bitshares on an exchange.  This risk is not a property of the BitAssets themselves.  We recomend that users never deposit BitAssets on an exchange and instead only use &lt;a href=&quot;/update/2014/12/18/Benefits-of-Being-a-BitShares-Gateway.html&quot;&gt;gateways&lt;/a&gt; that issue their IOUs onto the BitShares network.  This way you can trade your BitUSD against gateway IOUs without exposing your BitUSD to counter party risk while in the order book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;systemic-risk&quot;&gt;Systemic risk:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Systemic risk is a catch-all for other risks required to utilize the system.  The primary risk is individuals are responsible for protecting the cryptographic private keys that sign transactions proving ownership of assets.  These keys must be protected from theft or loss.  This risk can be greatly reduced and virtually eliminated by following best practices.  Systemic risk also includes the possibility of an overlooked fatal flaw in the open source software or the possibility of large scale failure of global network infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;outlook&quot;&gt;Outlook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BitShares market pegged assets are a viable open source alternative to the incumbent banking system.  Achieving price parity with a commonly used currency facilitates pricing and acceptance by merchants.  Additionally it reduces the need to calculate capital gains and losses on volatile assets to determine tax liability.  While certain risks of the system have been outlined, no system is without risk.  The current banking system allows private funds to be frozen or confiscated without consent, such as by court order or administrative actions.  Banks and financial institutions are susceptible to insolvency.  The availability and quality of banking service varies greatly throughout the world.  BitShares brings publically auditable open source banking to anyone with access to the internet.  Market pegged assets allow savers and spenders to choose preferred asset types.  This brings flexibility and ease of use to the open source banking experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>/article/2014/12/18/What-are-BitShares-Market-Pegged-Assets/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/article/2014/12/18/What-are-BitShares-Market-Pegged-Assets/</guid>
                
                
                    <category>article</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Benefits of Becoming a BitShares Gateway</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A gateway is a trusted party that facilitates moving value into and out of the BitShares network.  To do this they issue redeemable IOUs as fungible divisible assets on the BitShares block chain.  If the issuer is trustworthy then those IOUs will trade at face value and therefore be useful in trade.  This service is effectively that of a trusted party that facilitates trade among 3rd parties who do not know each other in much the same way that a bank issues cashiers checks so that 3rd parties can accept payment without having to worry about a personal check bouncing.  Unlike a cashiers check issued by a bank, the digital IOUs issued by a gateway are far more flexible and therefore useful.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BitShares network allows anyone to issue digital assets known as User Issued Assets (UIA).  These assets can be used to track shares in a company, deposits in a bank, and reward points among other uses.   Once an asset has been issued it can be freely traded against all of the other asset types on the network including the fully collateralized market pegged assets known as BitAssets such as (BitUSD, BitBTC, etc.).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide will provide a brief overview of the business opportunities available for those who wish to become a BitShares Gateway.   A Gateway provides the service of bridging external assets such as fiat dollars, gold, silver, and bitcoin into the BitShares network.   This service is critical to the success of BitShares because the vast majority of value must enter or exit the BitShares network through a Gateway or exchange. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gateway-vs-exchange&quot;&gt;Gateway vs Exchange&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people who have been around the crypto-currency space for a while are familiar with exchanges.  Exchanges facilitate trade by accepting deposits in two asset classes and maintaining an order book to facilitate trade among the assets using the deposited funds.   A deposit at an exchange is just an IOU that is tracked on an private database maintained by the exchange.      &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A gateway performs only 1 out of the 3 functions performed by an exchange: accept deposits and issue an IOU.  Gateways do not need to maintain an internal database tracking account balances nor do they need to maintain an order book.   This greatly simplifies the job of a gateway and minimizes risks to all parties involved.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today when you want to trade bitcoin for US Dollars you must deposit both your dollars and your bitcoin with a trusted third party.  If that third party happened to be Mt.Gox then you know what can happen to your bitcoins held on deposit: they can be stolen, lost, embezzled, or seized.  If Mt. Gox were simply a US Dollar gateway then only the dollar deposits would have been at risk because all orders and bitshares would have remained on the block chain under the control of the user’s keys. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the Mt. Gox example, a gateway has less than 50% the liability of an Exchange and users benefit from a global order book with no bitshare withdraw limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;generating-revenue-as-a-gateway&quot;&gt;Generating Revenue as a Gateway&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary reason for becoming a gateway is to earn a profit by providing a valuable service to the BitShares community.  Gateways have many ways of generating revenue.  The most straightforward method is by charging transaction fees every time someone moves value through your service.   You can also make money by charging users a fee every time they move one of your assets on the BitShares network and from market fees on the BitShares network.   In addition to transaction fees of various sorts, gateways also have an opportunity to generate revenue on the float they hold for their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-it-works&quot;&gt;How It Works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every single Bitcoin exchange is already performing a similar role to a gateway.  Users transfer funds to the exchange, the exchange tracks how much it owes each user, and when a user asks for a withdraw the exchange sends the funds back.    While the funds are on the exchange users can quickly and safely perform trades with other users of the same exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A BitShares gateway does the exact same process, the only difference is that the database that tracks the users’ deposits to the exchange is the BitShares block chain.   When a user transfers fiat dollars or bitcoin to a gateway, the gateway responds by transferring an IOU asset issued by the gateway back to the user.    When the user returns the IOU to the gateway the gateway sends fiat dollars or bitcoin back to the user.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IOU asset is tremendously useful to users in the BitShares ecosystem because it serves as a very flexible multi-party escrow asset.   Users will use an IOU USD from your gateway to trade against BitUSD and/or IOUs from other gateways.    Users will want to store value in BitUSD because it is mostly free of counter party risk, but when it comes time to convert BitUSD back to fiat USD they will do so through a gateway.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;legal-compliance&quot;&gt;Legal Compliance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any company that takes deposits from customers and facilitates transfers among customers is heavily regulated in most countries.   These regulations include license requirements, bonds, insurance, Know Your Customer (KYC) laws, and anti-money-laundering (AML) compliance among others.   The BitShares block chain provides gateways with all of the tools necessary to comply with these regulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are already in this business then you are maintaining a database tracking user deposits and your database is probably logging every single transaction and balance change.    Your database knows exactly who is owed what at any point in time.   You also have the power to seize or freeze user balances at the demand of law enforcement.    BitShares provides you with all of these features as well including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Ability to white-list public keys that may control a balance of your asset.
  2) Ability to freeze all funds and stop all trading of your assets.
  3) Ability to transfer any balance of your asset from any user to any other user. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, if you are operating a legally compliant crypto currency exchange, then you can easily expand your business to becoming a BitShares gateway.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a gateway you are likely very concerned about the safety of the funds you hold on behalf of your customers.   Fortunately moving your database from a custom internal system to the BitShares network provides your business with greatly improved security because you gain all of the benefits of a block chain.   Every transaction is logged in a public ledger and every balance transfer is signed and verified by 101 elected delegates distributed around the world.   The open source code is in use by many different gateways and peer reviewed by the entire industry.  You can rest assured that no funds will move without being properly signed by the private key of their owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the creator of a User Issued Asset you have complete freedom to honor funds or to reverse transactions as a result of theft by social engineering or a compromised user key.  No one can withdraw real fiat USD without your own review of the transaction history.   Any bugs in the BitShares code cannot result in your gateway losing money because you retain the authority over how to honor your asset.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the greatest improvement of security you gain by becoming a gateway rather than an exchange is that you only have to deal in a single asset.   Rather than having users deposit both dollars and crypto assets to your exchange, you can only allow dollar deposits and issuer dollar IOUs.    The BitShares block chain can then allow the user to trade directly with other users without having to transfer the assets to you and thus creating an additional liability of your exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the single biggest security liability your exchange faces as a gateway is guarding access to the private keys that control the user issued asset.   For this reason all User Issued Assets are controlled by a N of M multi signature system with both cold and hot keys.  You can divide access control among  many different individuals within your gateway to ensure that no single individual or single compromised machine can compromise control over your User Issued Asset. This is comparable to the need to safe guard the private keys of the crypto currencies an exchange holds for his customers.    It is critical that you guard these keys carefully and keep them in cold storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Access to your User Issued Asset is divided between the owner keys which maintain absolute control and should be kept in cold storage, and manager keys which can be kept on secure “hot” systems.   Every action of the Manager Keys can be undone by the Owner Keys.  This arrangement provides your organization multiple levels of control and maximum flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unlimited-opportunity&quot;&gt;Unlimited Opportunity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BitShares ecosystem is young and growing quickly.  Each and every day hundreds of thousands of dollars worth of BitShares are traded and one day that could grow to be millions of dollars.  The early gateways that establish trust and provide reliable service will likely become the default go-to gateway and have an opportunity to maximize volume of transactions they can charge fees on.   This early adoption will also result in added awareness of your company among our user base.  While you may start as a gateway you can also grow to provide other related services to the BitShares ecosystem such as hosted wallets or even becoming a delegate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;become-a-delegate&quot;&gt;Become a Delegate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BitShares community elects 101 paid delegates to help maintain and support the network.  As a gateway you are already maintaining a full node and keeping up with the latest network upgrades.  Their is almost no extra overhead to becoming a delegate.  Delegates earn over 50 BTS every 17 minutes or about $2500 per month at todays market cap of around $40M.  This delegate pay is already enough to pay for a part time position necessary to integrate BitShares with your companies database and website.   As the market cap grows it could potentially fund your business to expand the services it provides to the BitShares ecosystem.  &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>/update/2014/12/18/Benefits-of-Being-a-BitShares-Gateway/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/update/2014/12/18/Benefits-of-Being-a-BitShares-Gateway/</guid>
                
                
                    <category>update</category>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Why BitShares is Public Domain</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;When creating any kind of content whether a blog article or source code, the author has to make a choice about
which license to use.   This is a very tough decision for many people because, in theory, it impacts your ability
to make money from your content.  While I haven’t written an article on the subject of intellectual property, many
of my opinions are similar to those in the book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Against-Intellectual-Monopoly-Michele-Boldrin/dp/0521127262&quot;&gt;“Against Intellectual Monopoly”&lt;/a&gt;
by Michele Boldrin and Davik K. Levine.  As you can tell from the title I am very much against intellectual property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of my feelings on intellectual property, the fact remains that governments around the world recognize and 
enforce copyright.  If you don’t publish a license then you automatically retain full rights over your work and in theory
anyone who uses your work without your permission is guilty of copyright infringement.  In some countries you cannot
even release your rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to crypto currencies there are many additional factors that come to play. For starters, all serious crypto
currency projects must be open source so that the code can be audited and everyone using the system can have confidence
in the integrity of the network.  Most projects choose some variation of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MIT_License&quot;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; 
or &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BSD_licenses&quot;&gt;BSD&lt;/a&gt; licenses because they allow commercial and closed source usage 
and maximize the rate of adoption.  Licenses such as GPL are often not used because
it would limit adoption among some businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets review the BSD license:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Copyright (c) &amp;lt;year&amp;gt; &amp;lt;copyright holder&amp;gt;.
All rights reserved.

Redistribution and use in source and binary forms are permitted
provided that the above copyright notice and this paragraph are
duplicated in all such forms and that any documentation,
advertising materials, and other materials related to such
distribution and use acknowledge that the software was developed
by the &amp;lt;organization&amp;gt;. The name of the
&amp;lt;organization&amp;gt; may not be used to endorse or promote products derived
from this software without specific prior written permission.
THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED ``AS IS&#39;&#39; AND WITHOUT ANY EXPRESS OR
IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, THE IMPLIED
WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interesting thing about this license is that &amp;lt; copyright holder &amp;gt; reserves all rights and only grants
permission to copy or redistribute the software conditionally.  In a legal sense there is a owner and
that owner is potentially subject to liability.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A crypto currency is designed to be fully decentralized yet there exists a fully centralized owner who has
entered a legally enforceable contract with each and every user of the software.  In theory the owner of
the license could be coerced into revoking it or transferring the license to the government.  In theory the
government becomes the judge, jury, and executioner when it comes to interpreting and enforcing the contract. This 
simple license invites the government into the relationship between the creator of the software and the 
user thereof. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because BitShares was developed as part of a larger vision to make governments irrelevant, it would be a
contradiction to depend upon governments to enforce any kind of software license.  BitShares must succeed without
any kind of license protection at all.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;limited-liability&quot;&gt;Limited Liability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a software developer producing disruptive software that people are depending upon to store millions and hopefully
billions of dollars of wealth, there exists tremendous liability on the owner of the software if a fault causes a
loss of value to the user.   The BSD license attempts to absolve the owner of any liability, but that clause 
remains subject to interpretation of government courts.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I choose to put BitShares in the public domain because it should be owned by no one and everyone.  Once in the
public domain governments no longer have jurisdiction over it because there are no contracts to interpret.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If crypto currencies are to be truly free and beyond government control then they need to move beyond 
software licenses that depend upon government enforcement to have any meaning at all.  They need to wake
up and realize the internal contradiction.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;subjective-reality&quot;&gt;Subjective Reality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As some of you may know I take a subjective view of reality that sees everyone as part of one consciousness. 
Steve Pavlina has written a lot about this subject and ultimately decided to release all of his work into
the Public Domain.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stevepavlina.com/blog/2010/08/moving-beyond-copyright/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is what he had to say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Since I’m on the subjective side now, I see this situation in a different light than I 
otherwise would have. Bob and that ghostwriter and I aren’t separate from each other. 
They are me.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If I look within myself, I would say that the dream character Bob currently represents a 
part of me that feels phony and false. And why is that part there? Perhaps it’s because 
part of me feels phony and false claiming ownership of the material I’ve been producing and 
publishing for years.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The truth is that I can’t really say that I’m the one creating all this content. It flows 
through me so effortlessly that I don’t really know where it’s coming from. I spent thousands 
of hours producing all this content, but did I really create it? Sure I worked hard, 
but I overwhelmingly enjoyed the process. Writing is a peaceful, flowing, and pleasurable experience for me.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;When I write in the best way I know how (from inspiration), it’s like my consciousness steps aside, 
and content flows through me and onto the computer screen. I’m basically a pen. 
I let the dreamer communicate through me.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;How can I possibly blame Bob or his ghostwriter or anyone else who’s tried to pass 
off my material as their own? If I do that, I’d just be projecting my own issues onto them.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;I cannot solve this problem at that level. I could try of course, but what would that 
“solution” look like? Send Bob some nasty letters maybe. Get an attorney involved. Succumb 
to negative emotions like blame and resentment. Disconnect from who I really am. No thanks!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In the end, I’d only be fighting with myself, and I’d be injecting more conflict and 
negative drama into this dream world. That is not an intelligent solution.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;To be totally truthful, I have to confess that I’m in the same boat, trying to pass 
off the dreamer’s content as my own. I’ve been doing that for years. Bob is simply 
reflecting that back to me. The problem is mine, not his. I’m responsible for it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;To go a little deeper, I would say that I did write a lot of content 
(hundreds of articles) at the level of my own mind. But by and large, that’s the 
content that sucks. The best content, the stuff that makes people freak out the most, 
flows through me, but it is not of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this perspective relying on copyright and intellectual property seems downright counterproductive if our
goal is to create a more free and abundant world.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-public-domain&quot;&gt;What is Public Domain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based upon the reasoning above I have chosen to place everything I create into the Public Domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia defines the public domain as works that fall outside of copyright law. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Definitions of the boundaries of the public domain in relation to copyright, or intellectual property more generally, regard the public domain as a negative space, that is, it consists of works that are no longer in copyright term or &lt;b&gt;were never protected by copyright law&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I interpret this to mean that the work has no “owner” and ownership is the key component to control and
 therefore liability.  Ownership is centralization and is therefore a weakness in systems designed to
 be robust against attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rd-party-licenses&quot;&gt;3rd Party Licenses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BitShares isn’t entirely my work, but built on top of many libraries licensed under many different terms. 
Just because BitShares is Public Domain does not mean governments will not recognize the copyright of third parties
whose work is necessary for the function of BitShares.   Fortunately, placing my work in Public Domain still has
many theoretical benefits with respect to 3rd party licenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the software was owned by me rather than in the public domain then I, as the owner of the software, could be
compelled by government thugs at the behest of other copyright owners to comply with their terms.  By putting
BitShares into the public domain there is no one to compel except individual users which are so decentralized
that no sane individual would find it profitable to enforce their own copy rights against millions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when you download BitShares, only the code we created is actually in the Public Domain. If you use our code
along side 3rd party libraries then it will be up to you to comply (or not) with their terms.  Luckily all of
our dependencies have very permissive open source licenses (MIT, BSD, GPL, etc.) and as an individual user you
are still legally allowed to use the software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-am-not-a-lawyer&quot;&gt;I am not a Lawyer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything I have said in this post should not be taken as legal advice and could be entirely wrong.  Governments may
still impose liability against the author of Public Domain software even if the author is not the owner.  In my
experience there is little rhyme nor reason in how government courts actually interpret things.  The opinions I have
expressed are mostly based upon my own reasoning and philosophy. Your mileage may vary.  &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>/update/2014/12/17/Why-Public-Domain/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/update/2014/12/17/Why-Public-Domain/</guid>
                
                
                    <category>update</category>
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
